The world.
What a glorious place.
Seek freedom, and it will lie
stretched out before your eyes.
If the endless dream guides
your restless spirit,
seize it, raise your flag, and stand tall.
I think back to the time
when my search first began.
I left behind those shores of sand.
For the endless everlasting
world out there.
I know that with the
burning passion driving me.
Someday, somewhere, I'll finally see the
light I have searched for everywhere.
When the summer sun is shining.
Shaking the sails of my heart.
But I know the way the long moon's sea.
A brand new world that I have been hiding.
Has opened up its doors for me to go.
The way the long moon's sky.
Wearing in the troubled waves.
From all despair I can be saved.
For the horizon on the other side is.
And though I travel far
from where my search began.
Over seas of green and shores of sand.
Through the endless
everlasting world out there.
I know that with this
burning passion driving me.
Some days somewhere I'll
finally see the light.
I will search for everywhere.
What did you want to tell us, old-timer?
Listen up and listen good.
I've decided to tell you guys
everything I know about the Sky Island.
Most of this is rumor and hearsay,
so you'll have to make up your own
minds whether you believe it or not.
I believe it. Quiet!
There's something very strange that
happens in this part of the ocean.
Everything will suddenly
turn black as night.
Right in the middle of the brightest day!
Hey, yeah, the same thing
happened to us, right?
Yeah, it was like the sun vanished.
And then these enormous
monsters showed up.
You saw the giants.
There's a tale about where they come from.
But forget about them for now.
We can go into it later.
Now about this strange nightfall.
It's caused by the shadow
of an extremely dense cloud.
Cumulonimbus clouds?
But it was too dark for clouds.
It was like the sun went out.
Yeah, it was more of an eclipse.
Clouds on a cloudy day
are just sort of cloudy.
Yeah, just sort of cloudy.
Yeah, cloudy!
Shut your gums and listen!
This cloud is called a cumuloregalus.
It forms high in the sky, it has no internal
air currents, and never turns to rain.
No light can reach the ground, and a
sunny afternoon turns black as pitch.
It's like some giant hand reached up and
snuffed out the Sun like it was a candle.
Some say the cumuloregalus
clouds are floating fossils?
Petrified clouds that hang in the
sky unchanged for thousands of years.
You've got to be kidding us a Petrified
cloud that drifts around for centuries. Hey,
I'm just telling you
what people have told me
whether you believe it or
not Is entirely up to you.
So it's a mystery cloud.
Yeah, I guess that sums it up
about as well as anything else
You see there's only one
place this sky island can be
if it's real and that's on top
of one of those clouds. Yeah
that's
gonna be the
hard part because you'll
be risking your lives every
minute you mean like now!
There's only one way to get
there, the knock-up stream.
It shoots straight up in the air,
so it could theoretically take
you into the sky if you're lucky.
Wait a minute.
Are you trying to say this current
can actually send ships flying?
Great, then it'll be a snap.
All we have to do is hit to ride up.
Yahoo!
On an ocean current?
Except wouldn't we wind
up falling back into
the ocean and getting smashed into pieces?
Usually, that's true, unless you
can get the timing just right.
It's one thing to sit here all comfy and
talk about riding the knock-up stream
But if you think this trip is going
to be some kind of pleasure cruise,
you're in for a very rude awakening
The knock-up stream is as
dangerous as any hurricane
It should be avoided at all costs
But how exactly can a current of water
rise up in the air in the first place?
Come on, we've never heard anything
like that before, right guys?
I've heard a lot of different
explanations for the knock-up stream,
but there's only been one
that's made any sense to me,
though so far no one has been
stupid enough to try and confirm it.
It's like this.
Deep below the ocean floor, there
are large cavities filled with air.
Cool seawater seeps
into these air pockets,
and geothermal energy heats
it until it becomes steam.
Over time, the pressure builds,
And when it finally becomes too
great, there's a tremendous explosion.
This explosion hurls the water into the
air and creates a current to the sky.
The effect lasts for about one minute,
connecting the ocean to the
sky like a bridge. One minute?
Do you realize how enormous an
explosion like that would have to be?
The explosions occur in widely different
locations about five times a month.
We'd be blown into fish food
if we tried that old man.
Anyway, you can't really explain something
like this with words and theories.
It's one of the great
mysteries of creation.
So, so then,
we gotta ride this current
that shows up five times
a month into the air to
reach some island in the sky?
And just hope it's waiting for us?
I'd say that sums it up pretty well.
And if you miss, you fall back down,
slam into the ocean, and
get blown into fish food.
Just like you said.
Okay, so we're going to forget
about Sky Island, right?
Because it's nuts, Loopy.
It's completely insane.
You have to be luckier than Mr.
Lucky McLuckluck of Lucky Land on its
lucky day to pull off a set like this one.
It'll be okay. Let's go. Naturally.
How can you say it'll be okay?
Think about it for a second.
And what about the poor Going Merry?
Did you even stop to
consider the shape she's in?
The way she's suffering.
There's no way you could
expect her to stand
up to a disaster like
this in her condition!
He's absolutely right, she's worthless.
Even brand new, that wreck
wouldn't stand a chance. Say what?
Speed, weight, strength.
The explosion would blow that ship to pieces
before it had a chance to get airborne!
Yeah, see, it's hopeless.
But don't worry, I think
I can help you out there.
I'll have Mashida and Shoujo do
a complete refit of your ship.
I'll also have them reinforce the
superstructure to withstand the strain.
You bet!
Don't worry, guys, we're all over it!
Thanks, fellas!
Yeah, thanks a lot.
Have you really thought about this?
What?
Well, about...
Oh, yeah, how about the fact that at most,
we can only stay one more day on this
island, or did that slip your mind?
After that,
the Log Pose will lock on to the next
island's location and we'll have to move on.
That's right! That's right!
We gotta move on!
Hey, old man.
I realize you're not a fortune teller and
you probably don't have the vaguest idea.
But how many days will it
be until the next time the
knock-up stream lines up
with the cumulary gallus?
Or better yet, how many weeks?
Or months?
Or years?
Or centuries?
Now take your time.
I'm in no hurry.
Can I lend you an abacus?
It'll be at around noon tomorrow,
so you better get ready.
Wait a minute!
You mean we can make it?
Afraid so.
If you're scared, then don't go.
You're lying.
There's something fishy about this.
We've known you less than 24 hours.
Why are you being so helpful?
And what's more...
Now hold on, Uso.
Ah, you hold up till I'm finished.
This Sky Island, this legendary place
we don't even know the location of,
is just gonna show up out of
the blue at noon tomorrow.
And to help us get there, you're
gonna rebuild and reinforce our ship.
For nothing?
When something looks too good
to be true, it probably is.
The infamous liar Nolan is your
great-great-grand whatever, right?
So how do we know we can trust you?
Hey, old man! Soup's on! Come and get him!
Move it!
Nami!
What is it?
You want to fight me?
Mashida said, Whenever the
midday night occurs in this area,
a cumula regalis cloud appears
in the southern sky the next day.
Based on its usual cycle of
five appearances a month,
I'm guessing the knock-up stream
will also erupt tomorrow at midday.
That will probably also be to the south.
I can't be 100 % certain, but there's a
good chance the two events will coincide.
I'm proud to have met a bunch
of brave fools like you.
You're true pirates.
Now then, let's go inside and eat.
Tonight I want you to
call my home your home.
My friends.
Come on, Usopp, it's chow time!
Yeah, come on, you guys!
Chopper, go get Robin.
It looks like we're going to this Sky
Island, whether we're ready or not.
Well, let's just hope our
luck continues to hold.
Nami, do you think I'm a
spineless little coward?
You forgot to mention idiot.
And I know how you feel.
Now why not go apologize?
I'm sorry, old-timer. What are you doing?
Don't wipe that nose on me!
It's disgusting! Idiot!
Come over here, buddy, and get in with me!
Oh, yeah, keep it coming.
That really hits the old spot.
Eat up, everyone.
I'm just getting started.
There's plenty more on the way.
Gotcha, face! Oh, yeah!
It was hot sauce!
Come here, you squirrely
godly little face!
Hey, good-looking.
Want to sit next to me?
Whoa, shift down the gear, old man.
You're about a hundred years
too old to be hitting on Nani.
The skull's right eye.
That's where I saw the gold.
Those words smeared with tears are the
last ones Nolan wrote in his logbook.
The skull's right eye,
that's where I saw the gold.
That very same day, Noland was executed!
I still don't know what he meant by that?
Does it refer to the
name of a city or some
landmark that used to exist on the island?
Or is it just a poetic allusion
to his own impending death?
The blank pages that
follow give us no clue.
And that's the reason we continue
to dive to the bottom of the sea!
We dream.
Hooray for us!
We're gonna go flying!
Not if you keep eating
like that, we won't!
It's getting pretty dark, but I
can still make out the shoreline.
It's clear.
Drop anchor and prepare to land!
Golden treasure shouldn't be
wasted on starry-eyed dreamers.
Log Entry for May City, 1122.
Today I Arrived on Jaya.
Shortly after making landfall,
we were startled by the peculiar cries of
some strange bird from
deep in the forest!.
As well as the tolling of what
seemed to be an enormous bell.
The ringing of that golden
bell resounded far and wide!.
As if announcing the presence of some
great and prosperous city of the past.
Its fleeting echoes the
only reminder that this
land was once home to
a mighty civilization.
No land, no land?.
In our pride and arrogance,
we thought we had seen and heard
everything in our short lives!.
But the sound of that bell
tolling left us all speechless!.
It was as if the clang of that bell
had struck us all dumb with wonder.
I just love stories with bells?.
and them specially gold ones.
Hey, old-timer, it sounds like you just
might be a little fond of Nolan after all.
Look at this.
Wow, a golden bell.
Huh, doesn't seem too enormous to me.
None of these is the one Nolan
was writing about in his log book.
These are bell-shaped golden ingots we
found on the ocean floor during a dive.
Golden ingot?
The city of gold! Ha!
It is real.
It's still not proof, though.
You could find golden
relics like that lying
around in any old ruin in
this part of the world.
Maybe so, but it does suggest there was
a civilization here sometime in the past.
Ingots are made to divide gold
into standardized units of weight.
And that would indicate an
advanced trading society.
Right.
And you remember that peculiar bird call
he said they heard when they landed?
Show it to them.
There's more gold!
Just look at the size of it.
That's the last of them.
Oh, it's gorgeous!
Golden bells and birds, huh?
Do you think they might be symbols
of some ancient giant civilization?
I really couldn't say for certain,
but I'm pretty sure all these pieces
were part of the same casting.
This creature is called a Southbird.
You can still find them
on this island today.
Wow, and they have a peculiar call?
Uh-huh, just like in the logbook.
Sailors have used Southbirds on ships
since ancient times to help them to...
Oh no!
What's wrong?
This is really bad.
You guys got to get to the forest on
the south side of the island right away.
Huh?
What do you mean?
Are you crazy?
Don't waste a minute.
You got to capture one of
these birds and quickly.
How come? Why?
What do we need the bird for?
Now listen carefully.
Tomorrow you're going to
sail for the knock-up stream.
It lies directly south of here.
How are you going to get there?
We just sail the ship
due south, of course.
Have you forgotten this is the Grand Line?
You're heading for open sea.
You won't be able to get your bearings?
Wait, he's right.
Without a landmass to lock onto,
the Log Pose will be useless and
there'll be no way for us to navigate.
But there's got to be some way we can
figure out which direction to sail.
There is, if you can lay your
hands on one of these birds.
Certain animals are known to
have a very accurate internal
sense of direction as if they're
born with a natural compass.
That makes Zoro dumber than an animal.
Oh, yeah. Right.
Like you have any room to...
Talk.
The South Bird is a perfect
example of this kind of creature.
In the middle of a vast, barren
plain or a trackless ocean,
its body will always point
in the same direction.
You see?
If you don't get going to that forest
and catch one of those birds right now,
you'll have to kiss your only
chance to get to Sky Island goodbye.
And you're just telling us this now?
Quit your whining!
There's no time for that now. Go!
Move it or lose it!
You expect us to go stumbling through
the forest in the middle of the night?
Don't forget these.
The three of us are gonna get started
on the repairs to your broken-down ship.
You know, now that I think about it, we
probably shouldn't have had that party.
Oh, sure!
Now you tell us!
Listen, the clock's ticking.
You have until morning to catch a south
bird or you can forget
about the whole thing.
Whoa, it's pitch black.
Will you let go of me, you idiot?
My stomach's still so
stuffed from that dinner.
I couldn't catch a bird if I saw one.
So where are they?
Let's just catch one of them
and get back to drinking.
Will someone remind me how
we ended up in this mess?
Nanny couldn't tell us in the daylight.
It had to be in the middle of the night.
Where are the birds?
If I had any idea where the birds were,
do you think we'd be out
here looking for them?
All we know is this thing's
got a peculiar call.
Yeah, and it looks just like
that gold statue he showed us.
It's kind of hard for
me to believe that any
bird could look that
screwy-looking in real life.
Anyway, saying it has a
peculiar call is too vague.
We can't ID it from that.
Well, the old coot didn't seem to think
we'd have any trouble finding one.
Hey!
That sounded peculiar!
Oh, you think? Yeah!
Well, we're here.
Let's do it and get it over with.
Three nets, three teams.
Let's split up and bag that bird.
Right!
Let's go!
We're gonna beat up a bird!
We're trying to catch it!
Don't worry, Nami baby.
No matter what we run into,
I'm here to protect you.
Me too, Sanji Lump.
Will you suck it up and
stop being such a wuss?
Come on, guys, let's catch that bird.
Get out of here.
Okay, let's all settle down and see
if we can hear that bird's call again.
Hey, there it is!
Come on out! Moron!
Hey, why are you catching me?
Hey, nice accessorizing there, Nami.
Where'd you get that thing?
What thing?
Spider!
What?
It's just a spider.
Come here, you poor thing.
I hate spiders, you idiot!
Throw that thing away!
Get rid of it, Usoppity!
It's got to be poisonous!
They're falling from the trees!
This is just too nasty!
I bet you're a species of tarantula.
Don't worry, you guys.
They don't bite you unless you
make them angry or frighten them.
I used to wrestle with spiders
like this all the time.
Are you out of your tiny little mind?
Hairy bugs like that
completely freak me out!
Yeah, me too.
They make my flesh crawl.
Throw it away!
I can't stand it!
Oh, really?
But you don't seem to
have any problem with
the centipedes and moths
on the tree behind you.
Wait!
Don't leave me here alone!
Wait.
That sounded like someone screaming.
Really?
A centipede.
And a big one.
You don't have to kill
every living thing we meet.
It's kind of rude.
Yeah, well, he shouldn't
have snuck up on me.
Hey, wait now what you're
going back the way we came
There it is again, come on and be
careful not to step in the quicksand
Hey wait for
I gotcha!
It's an Atlas!
Atlas? That's right,
this one and the Hercules
beetle are some of the
most prized insects in
the world for collectors.
You mean there are people
who collect insects?
Oh yeah, and these guys are
some of the hardest to catch.
Hey, which one is cooler,
that bug or the One Piece?
That's a tough one.
Luffy, there's one over here too!
Oh yeah, meow, my stab beetle! Now!
Gotta catch it!
He flew away!
After him!
Don't let him get away!
A beehive! Run!
What the heck is wrong with this forage?
Luffy, look up there!
The bird!
He's the one who dropped the beehives!
What'd he say?
Did you understand him?
He said, I'll kill anyone
who disturbs this forest!
now now little boy you don't really
want to go and make us angry do you it's
not nice to show up in the middle of
the night and demand gold from someone
now get lost we've got a lot of work
to do and not a lot of time to do it
you must be the bodyguards and the
old man must be the ex-pirate cricket.
I heard the sad story of the
Montblanc family back at the tavern.
It moved me to tears.
But stealing another man's
treasure moves me even more.
I'm a pirate.
Cricket!
Maybe you'd like to know what people call
me before I take your whole life's work.
The hyena!